New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad Glass Negative Collection 2007.0055
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Glass Negatives, circa 1900-1922
  - Sleeping/State Room cars
    - 3/4 view of sleeping car 2001 with miller coupler, ornamental windowtops, and narrow vestibule (built by New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in 1882), circa 1900 (Box 3:, Folder 110)
    - 3/4 view of wooden sleeping car 2009 with closed vestibule, miller coupler, and decorative windowtops, circa 1900 (Box 3:, Folder 111)
    - 3/4 view of wooden sleeping car 2009 with closed vestibule, and decorative windowtops, circa 1900 (Box 3:, Folder 112)
    - Interior view of sleeping car 2009 with gas ceiling lamps, set up for day use, open section, circa 1900 (Box 3:, Folder 113)
    - 3/4 view of wooden state room/baggage car 2262 with full vestibule, and ornamental windows, photo taken from baggage end (built by Pullman Company), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 114)
    - 3/4 view of state room/baggage 2262 with full vestibule and ornamental windows, photo taken from state room end (built by Pullman Co.), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 115)
    - 3/4 view of wooden state room/baggage car 2265 with closed vestibule, appears new, photo taken from state room end (built by New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad in 1910), circa 1910 (Box 4:, Folder 116)
    - 3/4 view of wooden state room/baggage car 2265 with closed vestibule, photo taken from baggage end, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 117)
    - 3/4 view of steel Private Club Coach 5100 converted from coach 8015, circa 1922 (Box 4:, Folder 118)
  - Dining cars
    - 3/4 view of wooden dining car 2300 "Thames" with decorative windowtops, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 119)
    - Interior view of Dining car 2300 "Thames" with one and two seating, and gas ceiling lamps, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 120)
    - 3/4 view of wooden dining car 2302 "Niantic" with miller coupler, narrow vestibule, and round roof, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 121)
    - Interior view of dining car 2302 with two and two seating, ornamental chairs, gas ceiling lamp, and round roof, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 122)
    - 3/4 view of wooden dining car 2303 "Bronx" with arched windows, not opaqued, appears new, circa 1903 (Box 4:, Folder 123)
    - Interior view of wooden dining car 2303 with two and two seating plain chairs, circa 1903 (Box 4:, Folder 124)
    - 3/4 view of wooden dining car 2303 "Bronx" with ornamental, arched windows, not opaqued, circa 1903 (Box 4:, Folder 125)
    - Interior view of dining car 2303 "Bronx" with ornamental arched windows, circa 1903 (Box 4:, Folder 126)
  - Business cars
    - 3/4 view of wooden Business Car 100 with miller coupler and large center window, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 127)
    - 3/4 view of Private (Business) Car 200 with decorative windowtops and miller coupler, end platform on both ends (dismantled in 1923), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 128)
  - Invalid cars
    - 3/4 view of wooden invalid/funeral Car 950 passenger end with closed vestibule remodeled from parlor to invalid car, circa 1905 (Box 4:, Folder 129)
    - Interior view of invalid/funeral Car 950 remodeled from parlor car 2102 to invalid car, circa 1905 (Box 4:, Folder 130)
  - Freight cars
    - 3/4 view of wooden gondola car 2851 fox truck with split knuckle coupler with man operating gate, not opaqued, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 131)
    - Overhead shot of wooden gondola 2851 with locomotive in background (taken in New Haven, Connecticut), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 132)
    - 3/4 view of four 4-wheel wooden gondola cars 28254 with link and pin coupler, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 133)
    - End view of steel gondola 51637 with split knuckle coupler, not opaqued, circa 1907 (Box 4:, Folder 134)
    - End view of steel gondola 51637 with split knuckle coupler, not opaqued, circa 1907 (Box 4:, Folder 135)
    - Side view of steel gondola 51637 (built in 1907), circa 1907 (Box 4:, Folder 136)
    - End view of wooden boxcar 11729, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 137)
    - 3/4 view of wooden boxcar 11729, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 138)
    - Side view of wooden boxcar 86327 (built in 1903), apparently new, circa 1903 (Box 4:, Folder 139)
    - End view of wooden boxcar 86327, circa 1900-1905 (Box 4:, Folder 140)
    - End view of wooden boxcar 86327, circa 1900-1905 (Box 4:, Folder 141)
    - 3/4 view of wooden four-wheel caboose A216, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 142)
    - 3/4 view of wooden four-wheel caboose A216, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 143)
  - Wrecking cars
    - Side view of wreck crane "Derrick" with flat cars 7 and 8 carrying freight car trucks, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 144)
    - Wreck Train: Steam crane, 36 flat car with tool car (former baggage and coach cars), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 145)
    - 3/4 view of wooden tool car 11 (former baggage with clerestory roof, open end split knuckle couplers), circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 146)
    - Interior tool car, shows jacks, ropes, and drill bits, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 147)
    - Interior view of tool car, shows sledge hammers, saws, and padded bench, circa 1900 (Box 4:, Folder 148)
    - "Special Car Club" notice, possibly posted in car, circa 1900 (Box 5:, Folder 149)